<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<refentry>
  <refentryinfo>
    <date>1 November 2017</date>
    <productname>linstor</productname>
    <productnumber>1.0</productnumber>
  </refentryinfo>
  <refmeta>
    <refentrytitle>linstor</refentrytitle>
    <manvolnum>8</manvolnum>
    <refmiscinfo class="manual">System Administration</refmiscinfo>
  </refmeta>
  <refnamediv>
    <refname>linstor</refname>
    <refpurpose>Distributed configuration management for DRBD<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>linstor</primary>
    </indexterm>
    </refpurpose>
  </refnamediv>

  <refsect1>
    <title>Description</title>
    <para><option>linstor</option> is a utility for the simplified
    and automated administration of resources on a multiple-node DRBD 9
    cluster. It accomplishes this task by running a local server process on
    each member node of a linstor domain. As these local servers communicate
    with servers on other nodes, administrators can use any member node to
    control resources on all nodes of a linstor domain.<sbr/>
    </para>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
    <title>Quick overview of linstor basics</title>
    <para>
     The objects that linstor works with are <option>nodes</option>,
     <option>resources</option>, <option>volumes</option>
     and <option>assignments</option>. linstor keeps records describing these
     objects in its data tables.
     A <option>node</option> record defines a member node of a linstor domain.
     A <option>resource</option> record defines a DRBD resource for use with
     linstor, and <option>volume</option> records define the DRBD volumes
     of a <option>resource</option>. <option>Resources</option> can then be
     deployed on a number of <option>nodes</option>, thereby implicitly creating
     a number of associated <option>assignment</option> records.<sbr/>
    </para>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
    <title>Configuration</title>
	 <para>The configuration of <option>linstor</option> is stored in the
	 <option>control volume</option> of linstor. This has the advantage that
	 the configuration is distributed among all nodes in the cluster without
	 touching every node's configuration file manually. Please see
	 <option>modify-config</option> for further details.<sbr/>
	 In rare situations it might be nessessary to provide an initial
	 configuration (e.g., if the linstor control volume itself is stored on a
	 non-standard LVM volume group). For these situations it is possible to
	 provide a local configuration file, namely <option>/etc/linstord.cfg</option>.
	 This file has to provide a <option>[LOCAL]</option> section. Values allowed
	 in this section are: <option>drbdctrl-vg</option> and
	 <option>extend-path</option>. It is important to note that providing a
	 local configuration file is the exception and should only be used in very
	 rare situations.<sbr/>
	 </para>
 </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
      <title>Commands</title>
      <variablelist>
